[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 35]
Chuichui,
come here and take a look.
This is fine silk
delivered from Jiangnan.
Look at the pattern and fabric.
I'll have an embroiderer
make a wedding dress for you. How about that?
Chuichui.
Look.
I'll wear this for the occasion.
What do you think?
Are you crazy?
I won't marry you.
Of course you will marry me.
One day,
you will be willing to marry me.
Look.
These two pieces of clothing
look so perfect together.
Let go of me!
You bastard! Let me go!
Before you like me the way
you like Jiang Langxing
and before you're willing to marry me,
I won't let you go.
I will never like you!
You will.
What?
Are you still hoping
someone will come to save you?
It won't happen.
Neither Jiang Langxing nor Yan Xing
will come to save you.
I'm warning you,
don't you dare hurt them!
I won't hurt them,
unless they have a death wish.
Chuichui.
Chuichui!
In this world,
everyone only cares about themselves.
No one can be relied upon.
You only have me.
Only me.
What?
You're not slapping me this time?
Chuichui,
I truly adore you.
From now on,
I won't force you anymore.
I will wait patiently,
until
the day you truly fall in love with me.
Ms. Jin.
Excuse me.
Coming through.
-Yan Xing!
-Slow down.
Xing!
Mother.
You've been released?
Your father has a conscience.
He wrote a petition,
saying I'm a married daughter
and I'm already a member of the Yan family.
It was Minister Zhang.
He sent word to permit me to write it.
Grand Commander
sent people from the Imperial Security Bureau
to escort her with me.
Madam,
Grand Commander has already entered the palace.
Mother,
you've suffered.
I'm fine.
It's just your uncle.
Your uncle, he...
Your Majesty, please be clear!
"Joy and Sorrow" was composed by me!
It has nothing to do with Prince Xian!
It has even less to do with my clansmen!
Prince Xian and I
understand and appreciate each other, like Bo Ya and Ziqi.
All of this
is Lai Luozhi's conspiracy!
Your Majesty, please be clear!
Please clear Prince Xian's name!
Jin Zang!
-Mother!
-Jin Zang!
You dare to spout nonsense even at death's door.
Guards!
Put him in the urn!
Lai Luozhi!
How dare you torture him in public!
Lord Lai,
I have something else to tell you.
This secret
can only be told to you alone.
Step back!
You're a defenseless
musician.
I'd like to hear
what your
dying words are.
My clansmen and I
have suffered this calamity
all because of you!
-Uncle!
-Zang!
Who dares!
-Zang.
-Back off!
Uncle!
Chest.
Fire moth.
Xing.
You must deliver this blood-written letter
to the grand empress dowager.
Take good care of yourself.
You too.
Zang.
Uncle.
No!
Uncle!
Musician Jin!
Lai Luozhi!
You even dare to snatch the evidence
meant for the grand empress dowager
in broad daylight?
Back off!
What?
Jin Zang is dead?
When...
When did I...
order his death?
Musician Jin, unable to bear the humiliation,
cried out for Prince Xian's innocence
during the public procession,
saying it was all
a plot by Lord Lai.
Then he took his own life on the street.
This is the blood-written letter
Musician Jin left before dying,
Your Majesty.
Your... Your Majesty!
[I feel guilty towards Prince Xian.]
[I spent my life on music under Lai Luozhi's orders.]
When did I...
When did I
order the Jin family's death?
Your Majesty!
Jin Zang deluded the masses
and spread malicious rumors!
Even before his death, he tried to frame me!
I am utterly wronged!
Lord Lai, you inflated a trivial matter,
turning an ordinary banquet
into a bloodbath.
Now, with Musician Jin's death on the street,
the court is in an uproar.
The Imperial Investigation Department is no longer fit
to handle this case.
Your Majesty, please
entrust the Jin family's custody
to the Imperial Security Bureau.
Your Majesty!
You can't!
Enough!
You're still fighting for power even now.
You truly never give me peace.
Mr. Shen.
Since you're not afraid of getting your hands dirty
and insist on intervening,
the Jin family
shall be under your supervision.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
[Zichen Hall]
Your Majesty.
You are indeed a clever person.
But aren't you worried
that without my summons,
I could punish you
for barging into the palace in the middle of the night?
If you want to punish me,
I can only accept the punishment.
You know what?
Tonight,
I read
the music scores left by Jin Zang.
That was when I realized
he had accompanied me for so long.
Huan, you should
go easy on me.
How can I go easy in this game of Go?
Even if you lose,
I won't punish you.
No punishment for losing.
If I win,
can I get a reward?
What reward do you want?
If I win this round,
Huan,
let me be the crown princess, okay?
Okay.
It's a deal.
A wise man foresees the unseen.
Your Double Swallows move
seems simple,
yet brims with endless stratagems.
I...
I've lost this round.
Then you must keep your promise, Huan.
Okay.
I'll grant your wish.
From every dance I performed
after entering the palace
to every grand occasion of mine,
on every sleepless night,
his konghou
was never absent.
This composition is still unfinished.
He intended to perform it
at the ceremony after the Ming Hall
was rebuilt.
He never spoke much.
Never.
He was so quiet
that I often forgot
there was such a person.
As if
behind the curtains,
there was only a konghou.
When I was troubled,
this konghou
would play on its own
soothing melodies.
This konghou
will never sound again.
It's all my fault.
But
he's my only son.
You know what?
When I was little, I had my fortune told.
The fortune-teller said
my radiance was too great
and would burn those around me.
He also said
I would end up alone.
I was very angry at that time
and even had someone
beat that fortune-teller.
Now that I think about it,
he was right.
Not a single person
could accompany me to the end.
Mr. Shen.
I know
you've always wanted an answer too.
Once this matter
is completely settled,
I will give you an answer.
You're still up?
I'm thinking about my uncle.
I know you were close to your uncle.
It's natural to grieve.
I'll send you back to Yan's Mansion tomorrow.
Spend some time with Ms. Jin.
The dead cannot be brought back to life.
Grieving endlessly is futile.
I'm thinking about
what my uncle said
before he died.
Chest.
Fire moth.
Could it be that Musician Jin
discovered something about Fire Moth Sect?
My uncle was defenseless.
He knew clearly he couldn't
injure Lai Luozhi at all.
Yet before he died,
he still used every last bit of his strength
to lunge forward and tear at his collar.
Why?
Was it just to humiliate him?
[Lu's Pawnshop]
Has Chuichui returned?
Have you found Chuichui?
Where did she go?
If anything happens to her,
how can I face her
deceased mother?
[Lu's Pawnshop]
Don't worry.
I'll go look for her again.
I'll definitely bring her back.
Okay.
[Lu's Pawnshop]
[Lai's Mansion]
You really are not afraid of death.
You're just a constable,
yet you have the guts to trespass on Lai's Mansion.
Where have you hidden Lu Chuichui?
Do you know what you're talking about?
Jiang Langxing, a constable,
barged into Chief Censor's Mansion in the middle of the night.
He spoke disrespectfully, and it's an unforgivable crime.
Imprison him in the Imperial Investigation Department for punishment.
We constables
will never meet the same fate as Sun Tan again.
You're not skilled enough.
Go back now!
Commander Xu, you injured my men
without even hearing the fact.
You owe me an explanation.
Lai Luozhi,
you know clearly
what you did.
If this escalates,
who knows which of us
will suffer more?
And don't forget,
I can easily take things
from the imperial palace.
If you're hiding
something here,
I have my ways to retrieve it.
Chuichui.
Chuichui!
She's just a young lady.
You actually care about her so much.
You know nothing!
In this world,
I'm all alone.
Only she can understand me.
Only she truly sympathizes with me.
I'm your family too.
I'm your sister.
I won't forgive anyone
who ruins my plans!
I will
get rid
of them
one by one!
I've been thinking
about what method I should use
to make you disappear forever
from this world,
without him discovering it's my doing.
But
in poison and the art of killing,
he's more skilled than I am.
But now, I've figured it out.
Instead of killing you,
it's more important to make sure
he can never have you.
Commander Xu?
Chuichui!
Chuichui! Chuichui!
Chuichui. Chuichui.
How are you?
Let me see.
Are you hurt?
Chuichui.
It's me.
You fool!
What took you so long?
You're a big fool!
I... I went to Lai's Mansion to rescue you.
Commander Xu helped me.
That was when I knew
he already got you out.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I almost...
thought I'd never see you again.
I failed to protect you.
From now on,
I won't let anyone
hurt you again,
Chuichui.
I'm sorry.
What?
You were taken away?
When did that happen?
How come I didn't know that at all?
He didn't do anything to you, did he?
I'm fine.
I'm right here,
sitting in front of you, right?
Why did Lai Luozhi
suddenly kidnap you?
I'm afraid...
Chuichui was implicated because of me.
No,
that's not it.
Xing.
I'm sorry.
Actually...
there's something
I've been keeping from you.
Actually,
the friend
from the Imperial Investigation Department I mentioned
is Lai Luozhi.
Him?
In the beginning,
I always saw him in my mother's
graveyard.
I thought
he was a friend
with a ghost face mask who missed his deceased mother.
Later, he
coincidentally saved me once.
So... So I...
So I...
Until your third sister was poisoned.
The prescription he gave me
was indeed effective.
And he told me
not to tell anyone.
So...
So I held onto a glimmer of hope.
I thought maybe
he wanted to be a good person.
What am I supposed to say to you,
Chuichui?
Have you really read
too many plays?
How could you believe him?
Chuichui,
if Jiang Langxing and I
had arrived any later,
I'm afraid you would have been forced
to marry the Black Rakshasa.
Right,
Chuichui,
I remember your mother's grave
was lavishly built
by Uncle Lu.
Why would he
go there so often?
His mother's grave
happens to be
near my mother's grave.
I've been there once.
It looks like
an unremarkable lonely grave.
There's a name on it.
It's called Bi Luo.
Bi Luo?
Lai Luozhi's mother
actually had
such a beautiful name.
I think he was just
pretending to be filial
in front of Chuichui.
Here's what I think.
Lai Luozhi went to such great lengths
to get close to Chuichui.
I'm afraid it was not just
for her.
Right,
in Lai Luozhi's secret room,
I think I saw something.
It was... a coronation robe
for the emperor.
Lai Luozhi probably thought
I didn't know
what it is,
so he directly
showed it to me.
At first, I pretended not to care,
but later,
when I took a closer look,
I found what's embroidered on it
isn't a dragon,
but a Taotie.
Among the dragon's nine sons,
the fifth son, Taotie,
is the most insatiable.
It seems
Lai Luozhi's ambition
is now laid bare.
I have some matters to attend to,
so I'm leaving.
I'll walk him out.
You can't go.
Have you forgotten about Sun Tan?
Sun Tan knew clearly
that Lai Luozhi had treasonous intentions,
but due to the lack of concrete evidence,
he died in vain.
Now we know
there's a coronation robe,
yet you want to stop me?
I know you're desperate
to avenge Sun Tan and clear his name,
but don't forget,
Chuichui was taken away by you last night.
Lai Luozhi knows
she saw the coronation robe.
Of course he'll be prepared.
Are Lai's Mansion and the Imperial Investigation Department
harder to infiltrate
than the imperial palace?
When it comes to stealing,
as long as I set my mind to it,
there's nothing I can't steal.
Even if I'll have to dig three feet
into the earth, I'll find what has been hidden
by Lai Luozhi.
The title of Thief Saint
is indeed well-earned.
But now, Lai's Mansion and the Imperial Investigation Department
are probably already layered
with traps,
waiting for you to walk right into them.
It will be far more dangerous
than the imperial palace.
Shen Du,
why have you become so fussy?
Is this what happens
when a man gets a wife?
I'm afraid you'll soon
become like this.
Indeed, something's been off
in Xiang'an these days.
The 12 streets are full of people
from Nanlang and Xichen.
And they're securing street corners,
looking for houses, and renting shops.
It feels like something big is about to happen.
The Imperial Security Bureau has been keeping an eye on them.
I'm afraid you can only
keep an eye on a minority of them.
Shen Du.
If anything happens to me,
please take care of Yun Que for me.
Same here.
Goodbye, Grand Commander.
[Memorial]
Jin Zang,
play something light.
Jin Zang.
Your Majesty.
It's alright.
Today is the eighth day of the 12th lunar month.
The grand empress dowager should be rewarding the officials.
Why hasn't she appeared
at this hour?
Indeed.
Even Grand Commander hasn't shown up either.
The grand empress dowager suddenly felt unwell.
Today's matter of rewarding the officials
shall be handled by Lord Lai,
who will adjudicate based on
last year's precedents.
Yes, Your Majesty.
-Your Majesty, take care.
Then I'll act on behalf of the grand empress dowager
to
reward and punish the officials based on last year's performance.
How can Lai Luozhi be entrusted
with the power to reward and punish the officials?
Indeed.
The Imperial Investigation Department is merely a supervisory institution.
How can it overstep its authority like this?
This is utterly improper!
It's the grand empress dowager's edict.
Do you want her to worry
while she's ill?
You,
or you,
or all of you,
you want to defy the edict?
[As A Gentle Breeze]
[Visiting Card]
Lord Lai,
I am Director of the Ministry of Rites.
I am the secretary of the Ministry of War.
Reward.
[As A Gentle Breeze]
Reward!
Reward! Reward!
[As A Gentle Breeze]
-Thank you, Lord Lai.
[Mingsheng Temple]
Aunt,
Mother is now gravely ill,
yet she allows no one to visit her.
Prince Xian is still being grounded.
Lai Luozhi now holds all power in his hands.
Aunt,
now half of the court officials have gone
to swear allegiance in Lai's Mansion.
The other half are just waiting at home for their doom.
The court is on the verge of chaos!
The court is not in chaos yet,
but your heart is.
When your heart is not calm,
your mind is unsettled.
Aunt,
how can I calm my heart?
No matter what happens,
you are still the princess.
Why are you panicking?
Aunt,
you know better than anyone how much weight
this title of princess
truly carries.
His Majesty
still refuses to speak.
Although imperial physicians said
a sage speaks not in haste,
what if
he never speaks?
Now Mother is gravely ill.
If anything were to happen to her,
Aunt,
the position of Regent
would become the key
to controlling the entire court.
You want me to help you?
Of course.
You just said it yourself—
the title of princess
doesn't carry too much weight.
I have cultivated detachment for years.
I've long seen through worldly affairs.
No matter what happens,
just remember one thing:
assist His Majesty.
Aunt.
No need to rush.
This
is just the beginning.